(我愛羅)ママ…。
Mommy…
僕は…。
I…
(カンクロウ)うわっ！ すげぇな お前。
Hey, you're so cool!
(テマリ)わぁ～！
Wow!
(カンクロウ)う～ん…。
じゃあさ ごちそう作れるか？
Can you do food too?
(我愛羅)うん…。
(カンクロウ)おぉっ！ イカ焼き!!
Whoa, grilled squid!
(テマリ)わぁ～！
(カンクロウ)ラーメン！
Ramen!
(カンクロウ)う～ん… チェリー！
Cherries!
(カンクロウ)ロブスター！
Lobster!
(カンクロウ)う～ん… ウニ丼！
(テマリ)アハハッ！
Hmm…Sea urchin and rice bowl!
That's so cool!
すげぇ… すげぇ！
お前 すげぇぞ!!
That was terrific!
You're amazing!
う～ん…。
じゃあ…。
Okay then…
でっかいウンチ 作れるか？
How about a big pile of poop?
Can you do it?
テマリ。
Temari…
カンクロウ。
Kankuro…
(カンクロウ)は～い！
Yes!
我愛羅…。
Gaara…
テマリ！
Temari!
はい！
Yes!
気味が悪いぜ。
なんだ あいつ？
He's creepy…
What is he?
やぁ 怖い。
How scary.
マジで キモイ。
He's seriously creepy.
呪われたガキだ。
He's cursed.
Hey…Yashamaru…
(我愛羅)ねぇ 夜叉丸。
どうして
どうしてお腹って空くの？
Why…?
Why do we get hungry?
(夜叉丸)それはですね。
Well…
おいしいものを
食べるためかな？
That's in order for us
to eat good food, maybe?
そうか。
Oh, I see.
そうだね。
You're right!
夜叉丸の作ってくれるごはんは
おいしいよ。
The meals you make
taste good, Yashamaru!
ゴホゴホ！
ねぇ 夜叉丸。
Hey, Yashamaru…
なんで空って青いのかな？
Why is the sky blue?
そうですね それはたぶん
青い空を見ていると→
Well…
It could be in order for us
to gaze up at the blue sky,
透き通った気持になれるから
ですかね？
to make us feel
calm and refreshed?
そうか。
I see.
そうだね！
You're right!
僕 空を見上げてると→
When I look up at the sky,
少しだけ
胸の痛いのが安らぐんだ。
the pain inside of me feels
a little better.
ねぇ 夜叉丸。
Hey, Yashamaru…
僕 夜になっても
眠たくならないんだ。
I don't get sleepy
even when it's nighttime.
なんでかな？
Why is that?
それは困りましたね。
Now, that's a problem.
普通は目を閉じてると→
Normally, when you close your eyes,
you get sleepy.
眠くなるんですよ。
へぇ そうなんだ。
Really?
ねぇ なんで…。
Hey…
Why…Why don't I have a mother?
なんで僕には母さんがいないの？
それは…。
Well…
我愛羅様には
私がいるじゃないですか。
You have me, Lord Gaara.
私が我愛羅様の
おそばにいますからね。
Because I am at your side…
ずっと。
…always.
おっ！
あっ。
あぁ お弁当？
Oh…a boxed lunch?
ええ。
Yes!
(イルカ)え～ 体術というものは→
All right…
Taijutsu is namely,
いわゆる忍が生きていくうえでの
ひとつの… そうだな。
one of the essentials
for shinobi survival.
Let's see,
例えば 人が生きるということは
どんなことかというと→
when talking about human survival…
それは魚が川をのぼるという…。
It's like fish swimming
(シカマル)ハァ 面倒くせえ。
– Oh man, what a drag.
– their way upstream.
It's not an exaggeration to
call it the natural order of things.
What we have to think about is…
(チョウジ)うっ… うん？
(チョウジ)ん!? なに なに!?
Huh?! What the—?!
あっ エヘヘ…。
痛っ！
(イルカ)なに 寝ぼけてるんだ？
Ouch!
You're half asleep!
ん？
(チョウジ)あ～ シカマルでしょ もう。
It was Shikamaru!
Man, Shi-ka-ma-ru!
(チョウジ)シカマル！
フンッ。
えっ？
はっ！
Take that!
ほい この！
And that!
You—!
(ナルト)も～ お前たちってば→
Hey, you guys…
うるせえんだってばよ。
Will you pipe down?
寝てらんねえじゃんかよ。
I'm trying to sleep here!
(イルカ)
おい ナルト 今はな 授業中なんだ。
Hey, Naruto!
We're in class.
寝る時間じゃ…。
ヘヘヘ…。
Now is not the time…
ないだろうが！
to sleep!
ナルト！ シカマル！ チョウジ！
３人とも廊下で立ってろ!!
Naruto! Shikamaru! Choji!
You three, go stand in the hallway!
(３人)えぇ～。
(イルカ)えぇ～じゃない！
– What?!
No "whats"!
(３人)は～い。
– Yes, sir…
あ～あ
またイルカ先生 怒らしちゃった。
Man… Iruka Sensei got mad
at me again.
(チョウジ)えっと…
お お菓子あるけど 食べる？
Um…
I-I've got snacks. Want some?
おぉ～！
Oh!
シーッ。
ヘヘッ。
食べるってばよ。
I'll totally have some!
どうだ お前たち？
少しは反省している…。
Okay, guys, have you thought about
the way you've behaved?
ほんと お前たちは…。
Good grief, you guys.
わっ！
ハハハハ。
イルカ先生ってば…。
Iruka Sensei!
You scared us, ya know!
びっくりしたってばよ。
(シカマル)ぶっ殺す。
(チョウジ)えっ なに!? なに!?
I'm gonna kill you…
Huh?! W-What happened?!
(チョウジ)あ～ やっぱここだ。
I knew I'd find you here.
ねぇねぇ シカマル お金貸して。
Hey, Shikamaru.
Can you lend me some money?
なんだよ お前 またお菓子か？
Why? Snacks again?
そうそう。
Yeah!
だって お菓子以外に
何か買うものなんてある？
I mean…what else is there
to buy besides snacks?
もう 面倒くせえなぁ。
Aw man, what a drag.
そんなやつは お前だけだよ。
You're one in a million.
ヘッ。
なんだ その目。
気持わり～。
What's with your eyes?
So creepy!
Don't look at us!
こっち見んな。
変なんだよ お前。
You're weird.
なあ なあ なあ なあ
もうやめろってばよ。
C'mon, cut it out!
こいつが お前らに何かしたのか？
What'd he do to you anyway?!
は？ なんだよ ヒーロー気取りかよ。
What? Trying to act like a hero?
弱い者いじめはするなってばよ。
Don't bully people weaker
than you, ya know!
ん？ うぜえ。
Shut up!
フン！ しらけちまった。
おい みんな行こうぜ。
Humph! This is boring!
Let's go, guys.
あ～あ つまんねえの。
行こう行こう。
So boring.
– Let's go.
– Yeah, let's go.
なんだよ あいつったら
面倒くせえことして。
Man, what a drag.
Doing stuff like that.
他人の世話
焼いてるヒマがあったら→
Instead of butting into
other people's business,
he should polish his skills.
自分の術でも磨けっつうの バカナルト。
Stupid Naruto.
バカって言うな。
(シカマル)え なんだ？
Don't call him "stupid."
Huh? What?
ナルトは バカじゃない。
Naruto is not stupid.
だって シカマルだって→
Even you said before, Shikamaru…
将棋の駒は数が揃わなきゃって
僕のこと…。
You said all shogi pieces
are necessary.
You said that about me.
え？ お前 なに言ってんだ？
Huh?! What are you talking about?
さっき お金貸さなかったから
怒ってんだろ？
You're just mad at me
from earlier
because I didn't loan you
any money.
違う！
You're wrong.
ナルトは… ナルトは シカマルなんだ。
Naruto is…
Naruto is like you, Shikamaru!
バカって言うな！ 取り消せ！
So don't call him "stupid"!
Take it back!
チッ… 面倒くせえ。
Sheesh!
What a drag!
いいから
ちゃんとわかるように話せよ。
Then speak in a way
I can understand!
ぼ… 僕に命令すんな。
Don't…
Don't order me around!
お おい おい！
お前ら なにしてんだってばよ！
Hey, hey!
What are you guys doing?!
お前ら仲よしじゃん！
You're friends, aren't you?
なんでケンカしてんだってばよ。
おいって！
Why are you fighting?!
Hey!
この… このデブが
文句言ってくるからよ！
This…
This fatso started complaining!
シカマルの目は 節穴だ。
僕は デブじゃない。
It's because you're blind!
I'm not a fatso!
ん～。
ポッチャリ系だ！
I'm pleasantly plump!
このケンカ 俺が買うってばよ！
All right!
Let me buy into this fight.
(チョウジ/シカマル)え… なにそれ？
Huh…?
– What are you talking about?
あっ じゃあ そのお金で
お菓子を買う！
Oh! Then I'm buying snacks with
that money you're gonna pay me.
(ナルト/シカマル)え～っ！
– What?
– Huh?
なにそれ？
What did you just say?
(３人)ハハッ…。
(シカマル)なんだよ それ。
(ナルトたち)ハハッ。
What was that about?
(シカマル)おもしれえ。
That's so funny.
(ナルトたち)アハハッ。
バッとさ やっちゃってさ→
I did that…
そんで いつものとこに
行ったってばよ。
and then, I went
to the usual spot.
Huh, so that's what happened.
へぇ そうか。
(チョウジ)ナルト お菓子食べる？
Naruto, want some snacks?
おっ サンキュー！
Oh, thank you!
フッ。
ん？ おい あれ！
(２人)ん？
Hey, look!
(シカマル)わ～ マジかよ 面倒くせえ。
What? Seriously?
What a drag!
(ナルト/チョウジ)やだやだ 女やだ。
– Nope, nope.
– No girls for me!
(ナルトたち)あっ やべえ！
– She's after us!
Over here!
You wait!
I can't go any further!
(チョウジ)ダメ…。
こっちへ逃げろ こっち…。
Ino's coming! Keep running!
もう無理。
I can't!
(ナルトたち)ハァ ハァ…。
いののやつ 怒ると すげえな。
That Ino…
She's terrible when she gets mad!
ありゃ 絶対売れ残るよ… ハァ。
I swear she's gonna end up
an old maid.
ほら あそこあそこ！
(シカマル)え？
Hey! Over there, over there!
スケベ～なイルカ先生 発見だってばよ。
I spy a Pervy Iruka Sensei!
おい ナルト。
Hey, Naruto…
あれ やるか？
マジ？
Wanna do "that"?!
Are you serious?
おお！
うん。
Yeah!
ねぇ いいでしょ？
(イルカ)え？ いやぁ まいったな。
Oh c'mon…
What? I don't know what to say.
お… なんだ ナルトか。
Oh…
It's you, Naruto.
こんな時間に出歩いて
子供は寝てる時間…。
What're you doing out so late?
Kid should be in bed—
お色気の術！
Sexy Jutsu!
See ya later, Naruto.
あ～っ くっ…。
Your Sexy Jutsu was awesome!
Bye-bye, Naruto!
Hey, hey, Shikamaru.
ギャハーッ！
It's curry night at my house tonight.
キャーッ！
That sounds good!
I'm getting tired of
my mom's cooking.
See you tomorrow!
じゃあな ナルト。
お色気の術 すごかったぜ。
Yeah!
See ya tomorrow!
Hey, why don't we talk about
our dreams tonight?
バイバイ ナルト。
ねぇねぇ シカマル
僕んち 今夜は カレー曜日。
(シカマル)いいな 俺
母ちゃんの作るメシ もう飽きた。
(シカマル/チョウジ)ハハハッ。
また明日！
(シカマル)おお！
(チョウジ)明日ね！